When I say I was almost in Squid Game, I specifically mean Netflix's reality show version,
not like the actual one where people died. Sorry for a bit of a bait there, but also I'm not lying,
so before I get into that whole story, I need to explain how I was even put in that situation
to begin with. Early last year, Jacob, our friend Joe, my brother Jax, and I all went to this
little Squid Game pop-up event hosted by Netflix. It looked interesting, to say the least,
a combination of curiosity and boredom are what convinced us to buy tickets. Our Uber took us to
the location provided, and we were dropped off at a scary back alley in the streets of LA.
Are you sure this isn't a setup for, you know, the real thing? We hunted down the entrance,
headed up Squid Game themed stairs, and inside was a big lobby with merch, snacks, decorations.
You know what else was in there? No other human beings. We were the only ones there,
along with the shape guys that were just staring at us. Are you sure? This isn't- I don't know
anymore. Staff signed us in and gave us numbered wristbands. What? It's like Squid Game!
Eventually more contestants showed up, and soon enough we were hurried into the starting room,
decorated very much like no one actually cared about this thing. And if they did, corporate
ruined it. The staff guy gave us the rundown on how the event was going to work, all the rules,
such and such. But sprinkled throughout the explanation, we're like, a lot of safety hazard jokes.
I know the concept of the whole thing is rooted in playing dangerous games and dying, and ooh,
evil dystopian. But he was saying things like, don't lean on the walls. You might rip through it,
and I don't want to fill out any paperwork if you hurt yourself. Don't touch anything that you
shouldn't touch. I don't want to have to fill out paperwork again. He was very anti-paperwork,
like way more than the actual human safety part. Based on what we've seen so far, our group knew
we were about to experience exactly what we were hoping for, but with not the death part.
For the first game, what we were led into a room with lines of glass squares. What? It's like
Squid Game again, the glass jumping part. When it was your turn, the pattern on the 10 squares
would be shown, and you needed to memorize which tiles to step on. It's like, well, I guess it's
kind of like, Squid Game kind of. The first batch of people stepped up, the patterns all flashed.
But before anyone could begin stepping on glass, they were instructed to hold it, and only take
one step at a time. For the whole game, we had to watch everyone take one individual step,
stop, wait to be confirmed, then take one more step, for 10 spaces, in like, six groups total.
Also, I think that whatever mechanism they used to track if people were out or not was super
busted, because literally, only like five people in total got their pattern right. Joe, Jacob,
and Jacks all swore they memorized their pattern correctly, but were eliminated anyway.
I know I botched mine up though, I've got paper-shredder rain. They could give me one tile to memorize,
and I would still forget it. 25 of the 30 people failed their very first puzzle.
Now, Netflix knew that if people paid 40 bucks, yeah, 40, to be in this shitty
Squid Game event, and then had to go home after the first game, they would be pretty upset.
So the rule was, for the first four challenges, no one would be eliminated.
Yay, woohoo! Phew, that was a close one. In the next room, they tried to combine both the
Honeycomb Game and the Marbles Game from the show, but what was put together was throw marbles
in the shape on the table to win other people's marbles. It was very anti-glamactic.
Unfortunately, we were only able to gather in groups of three, so Joe wasn't able to join us.
Instead, he was paired up as a third wheel to a random couple that was obviously here on a date.
Jack's cleaned up shop on us, he got all our marbles within minutes, but over at Joe's table,
malicious injustice was afoot. Apparently, the two people that were in a romantic relationship
ganged up on Joe, and after taking all his marbles, just split them up between each other.
Despite there being no actual stakes in the game, Joe was furious simply out of principle
and swore to get revenge on them somewhere somehow. Before he could even start any beef,
we were brought into the next room, and again, we're split into groups this time of four.
They really liked group activities in this thing. Welcome through the doors to the challenge,
everyone was stationed around a respective gift coffin. After opening them up, it was revealed
we were going to be playing a big version of operation. The game where you try to pick up fake
little organs with fake medical tools without touching the sides, so simulated surgery.
Like, I guess that was kind of in squid game, at least they decorated the boxes like it,
but I mean, we're really pushing it at this point. Jacob and I randomly got paired up with
this married couple, and the four of us started inspecting the tools. When suddenly, the woman goes,
oh will you pass me the forceps? She's a surgeon.
Oh my god, we just happened to be paired up with a lady whose literal job was operation.
The challenge began and the three of us took our hands off the tools, she cracked her knuckles,
and we watched as all the plastic organs were suddenly out of the prop body. Not surprisingly,
our team was the first to finish. When we got back together with Joe and Jack,
we explained how we got super lucky to be paired up with an actual surgeon that literally
soloed the whole thing, and Joe was like, wait, that guy was a surgeon? And Jacob and I had to
shake our heads and say, no Joe, she was a surgeon. Damn it. Now that we were entering the fourth
challenge, it was time to get serious. This was the first game where people would start getting
eliminated for realsies, but not realsies. Everyone was split into two groups and taken to one side of
a wall where there was a bunch of prop boats. It was a kind of not really IRL version of battleship
where we had to try and shoot down all the other side's boats, and the team that one would progress
into the fifth game. I would describe this idea as good enough. Sure, you know, we didn't get to
choose where to put our boats since they were bolted to the floor, but I guess we did only pay 40 bucks
to be here. For some reason though, the staff member on our side was, we can call it extremely
helpful. At first he was saying general tips, like, so if they still have a four tile boat,
let's check all the areas that could fit that, you know, saying vague hints to help us out a bit.
But by the end of it, he was just straight up telling us if I were you guys, I wish you right here.
Like, this guy wanted us to win, and win fast, so either he had some kind of bet going on with
the other staff members, or dude just had places to be. All the other team's boats were sunk,
and the remaining 15 or so people were led into the semi-final game. It was obvious as soon as
we saw her. We were finally playing the classic red light green light. It was decorated like the
show the doll was there, but there were giant gift boxes scattered around the room to act as obstacles
because when you think about it, red light green light isn't high stakes when staff can't actually
shoot the contestants. Like, something had to be added to spice it up a bit. We gathered on the
starting line and the game started. As we were playing, I was thinking how are they measuring
if we're moving or not. You know, I doubt they recreated the entire motion tracking doll thing,
just for this pop-up that's getting torn down after a month. I figured the only thing they could
be using to track motion is our wristband, so in between the green lights, I focused extra hard
on making sure my wrist stayed as still as possible. In fact, I was focusing so hard on my wrist
that I didn't even realize I was the first one to pass the finish line. Unfortunately,
similarly to the jakey glass memory game, it seemed like a lot of the wristbands were super
wonky as well because a lot of people got pinged as eliminated no matter how still they were,
including Jacob and Jacks, which was a huge buzzkill. Either that or they were just built to be super
sensitive and somehow my weak little carpal tunnel wrists decided to not shake for the first time
in five years. I turned back to see just three people left, one of them being Joe. They all
lunged forward and as red light was called for the final time, I watched as Joe tripped and crashed
into them, causing every person left to topple to the floor. Their wristbands deemed them eliminated.
As Joe was walking past me to the dead area, I asked what happened to which he said,
I got him. Joe had intentionally sacrificed himself to bump those people because they were the
couple that ganged up on him during marbles. He had finally gotten his revenge. Was it petty?
Yes, did he probably ruin their date? Yes, but do I also not care and think that was the funnier
shit ever? Absolutely, Joe is awesome. I was somehow the only one in our group moving onto the
final round. Me and the other four winners of red light green light were brought into
Squid Game. And everyone else was there too, watching from behind a little rope.
Jaden, Squid Game is so rough and tough. How did you fare against the four other dudes that made it
to the end? In real Squid Game, the guy got stabbed. Did you get stabbed? You're probably wondering.
And oh dear viewer, no, I did not get stabbed. In fact, I didn't get hurt at all because Netflix
didn't want to deal with paperwork. Instead, we played, hold the fake egg on a spoon and attack
each other until there's one egg standing, but attack in a way where there's no paperwork,
which is fine with me because I doubt any of us actually knew how to play Squid Game anyway.
The buzzer rang and everyone started shifting around in the shape. Since I, for some reason,
have experienced in high stakes and game tournaments, I deployed my signature strategy of don't bring
attention to myself. I simply dodged and weaved between the guys swiping at each other's eggs.
I can take someone on in a 1v1, but any number higher and I've gone well past my capabilities.
Eventually, there are just three people left. The crowd started yelling,
get the girl, the girl's still in, and the two guys started walking towards me. But then
my personal peanut gallery chimed in with, hey, hey, hey, they're ganging up on the girl,
boom, shame, boom. And that flustered them enough to back away again.
Apparently, the power of teamwork and fear of misogyny can persevere through anything.
Suddenly, an egg hit the floor. It was just me and non-woman-hating guy number two.
The exact 1v1 I was trying to create. We circled each other. Both our spoon-holding arms stretched
out as far as they could go. He swung at my egg a couple times and I managed to dodge,
but I couldn't win this thing if I didn't go on the offense. Wait, what if I just...
I won the silly little Netflix Squid Game pop-up. The frontman came out and escorted me to the VIP
area where he gave me a plastic animal mask like in Squid Game. And we took awesome photos together
and I got an awesome t-shirt that said winner. And I didn't know it at the time, but as this was
happening, the staff pretended to shoot all the losers with fake gun sounds. Unfortunately,
I didn't get the 45.6 billion money prize like in the show. But along with the t-shirt,
they did give me a special form to fill out that would give me a priority application for Netflix's
actual Squid Game reality show. Squid Game, the challenge. Season 2. I looked at the form and thought,
you know, we'll just see what happens. Filled it out and was able to bring my friends back to
the VIP room with me because winning isn't fun unless you do it with your friends. That's what
Squid Game taught me. There were a bunch of snacks and alcoholic beverages in the winner area.
And I gotta say, the alcoholic squid drinks were probably the worst things I've ever tasted.
It was astonishing how bad they were. Over a year later, and I can... Oh, I can still imagine it.
I don't even know what ingredient could do that to a drink. Anyway, after I submitted my form,
I have expected to never hear anything about it ever again. But to my surprise, Netflix reached out
to interview me about potentially being a contestant on the show. In fact, I was forwarded to the next
round of interviews three times to completely break any potential rules of confidentiality. I was
starting to think there might be a chance I could actually be on the show. But eventually,
the interviews came to a stop, and I have come to the conclusion they have moved on to better qualifying
people. Most likely because I will admit I was a bit too honest during the interviews. They basically
all just looked like this. What kind of a role do you think you would play in Squid Game as a contestant?
I'd probably just be a follower. I don't like taking charge at all. How hard would you fight
to win Squid Game? Not that hard. Have you watched the first season of Squid Game the challenge?
No. Well, I watched the first 20 minutes, but I turned it off because I thought it was really
badly paced and boring. So that was that. And I'm okay with it. Or who knows? Maybe they saw my very
strange track record of winning game tournaments and got scared. It kind of seems like those kinds
of really intense and active game shows like real-life Squid Game end up having a lot of people complaining
about how they got hurt or weren't treated all that great anyway. So I'm glad I'm sitting safe
and sound in the comfort of my own home. I'm glad I'm not dealing with Squid Game related injuries.
In fact, also a very quick reminder that Techware Merch is going away soon. If you're late to
watching this video, it's probably already gone, to be honest. Sorry. I tried to warn you. Thanks
for watching though. And see you later.